Why is it so easy for some people to learn Spanish?
And for others, however, is it very difficult?
Why do some students living in Spain
They don't speak Spanish well, but other students who do
live abroad, speak Spanish perfectly?
Why do some people speak Spanish only in one year,
and there are other people who need 5, 6, or
still, they don't even speak Spanish?
Hello, Hispanophiles!
And welcome once again to Spanish with Vicente.
My name is Vicente and I am an online Spanish teacher.
And in today's video... I'm going to talk to you about
Tips for learning Spanish, for improving your Spanish,
and so that your Spanish learning process,
or even any language that is easier for you.
Are you ready? Go ahead!
Well, now that you're watching this video,
You might ask yourself, "And who are you to give me advice?"
how to learn a language, or how to learn Spanish?
Well, first of all, I am a Spanish teacher,
and more or less, I have an idea of how the students
have learned the language. What has been a bit of their surroundings,
your background, what are you saying, what have been your methods
to learn, or what have been your main resources
etc. But not only that, I am not just a teacher,
and I know a little about how students, or my students,
learn Spanish. But also, I have been, I am, and I will be
foreign language student.
And that's why I want to share these tips with you.
so that you too can learn a language,
as easy as possible.
Well, let's start with a piece of advice that will be
Let's say, the top of the pyramid. That's going to be the key advice.
The advice that you all should follow,
if you are learning Spanish or any other language.
And this advice is to get into the language.
which is what is called being or living in a context
language immersion. What if you live in another country?
You don't know anyone who speaks the language, or simply,
You don't like leaving home to learn the language.
Because there are also people who don't like to go out
from their own home, to learn a language.
With each of the tips I'm going to give you, you're going to see
that it is completely possible to learn a language.
Let's get started. The first piece of advice I give you, and I've taken it
as a reference because many students in the long run,
After a long time, they end up getting tired of learning
a foreign language. To learn Spanish, for example.
The first advice I'm going to give you is
that you do what you like.
Learn Spanish with what you like.
If you like to paint, learn Spanish by painting.
If you like taking photos,
Learn Spanish by taking photos. Why?
Because here a very important factor comes into play,
which is that of motivation.
Above all, intrinsic motivation, which is the motivation
that a student has inside. Therefore, if you,
As a Spanish student, you are learning Spanish
with something you really like and are passionate about,
It is much more difficult for you to stop learning Spanish.
Before continuing with the advice, I want to ask you to
stop the video, and write in the comments, what advice
Would you give me, or other Spanish students,
to learn Spanish in an easier way.
The second piece of advice I'm going to give you, I'm sure
that you've seen on any blog, on any channel,
and everyone says it, watching series and movies,
listen to music, and read books.
Does this really help? Yes, it helps, but...
We have to know how and when to watch movies, listen to music
and read books. I'll give you an example,
If you are a student who has just started
to learn Spanish, and you put on a movie from the 70s,
from a very good Spanish director, a Spanish film,
You may not understand anything, you may not understand the expressions,
you don't even understand the language or vocabulary
that they use in this movie. So that's going to do it
that you get tired, that you stop learning.
My recommendation is that you go by levels, if you are starting
to learn Spanish, don't watch a movie for example,
based on a Spanish neighborhood, because the vocabulary of
that movie, it's not going to be of any use.
Next, if you already speak Spanish, and want to improve it,
Reading is good. Yes, but what are you going to read?
Read something you like. For example, I'm going to put
My personal example is English. For example,
I love reading books about motivation, about business,
about marketing, etc. I have here 2 of my latest books,
And well, I love reading them, I try to read a book every month.
But, every 2 months, what I do is that I buy
a book in English. In this way, little by little,
I'm adding English, and in your case,
It could be Spanish, in my habits.
The next piece of advice I'm going to give you, and that is
completely free, is that we are surrounded by technology,
We have technology everywhere. I have the technology.
in my hand, and I have technology right in front of me.
What's up? This technology is smart, simply
you have to take your mobile phone,
Go to settings, OK? And change the language to Spanish.
That way, every time you pick up your phone,
You're going to see it in Spanish, you're going to be learning something
that you already have memorized in your head.
You will know what the message icon is, but
You'll see it written in Spanish. You'll see what it is.
the settings icon, and you will see it written in Spanish.
Another piece of advice I'm going to give you, very important, is that
you have the help of a teacher. Someone specialized.
Just like if you want to, for example, lose weight,
You will have the help of a nutritionist. Or if you prefer,
To gain health, you will have the help of a doctor,
When learning a language, you have to take into account
with the help of a professional.
Many students come to me,
and they tell me that they have a beginner, intermediate level,
because they learned it on a mobile app.
And when I ask those students:
"How are you? How are you today?" they reply.
Well.
If you want to speak like a person in Spanish,
you have to talk like a person.
You don't have to talk like a machine. You have to see
how that person moves, how that person speaks in Spanish.
There is a very big, very big difference, believe me,
among students learning Spanish
with a mobile application, and students
who learn Spanish with a Spanish teacher
as a foreign language, a very big difference.
I assure you.
The following advice may seem very difficult, but
Believe me, it's the easiest: Speak Spanish. Period.
Yeah, but... I live in the United States.
Yes, but... I live in Brazil.
There are Spaniards all over the world.
There are Meetup groups.
There are groups on Facebook. There are probably groups in your city.
where you can go once every two weeks, and meet someone.
Ask him, "How are you?" "What's your name?" "Share your opinions."
talk about a common topic.
I'll give you my example. I'm a pain, but
That's how I learn English. Right? Or how I maintain
my level of English. There are many British people in my city.
What I do is that one day a week,
On Sunday mornings, I go to a British cafe,
to have a "British breakfast".
Vegetarian, by the way.
That simple act of going to the cafeteria for breakfast,
It already makes me have to speak to the waiter in English.
I speak English! I order in English!
And if you are a little extroverted, you can ask him
How was your day? Are there a lot of people around here today, aren't there?
How was yesterday? That simple gesture is already making you
Activate your brain, be active. You can go to a coffee shop,
You can go to a store, I don't know, anything.
The next tip is: Have a calendar.
But a calendar for what? Well, a calendar.
to write down everything you learn, day by day.
And what's a calendar for? One of the most useful things
what I did when I was abroad, was
write down all the words I learned on a calendar,
So, I'm going to show you this calendar, for example,
This is from February, so every day that passed,
I would jot down a new word. For example:
Friday, February 1st, and I wrote down a word
that I had learned that day.
And if that day I hadn't learned any words,
I was looking for an article on the internet, a news story on television,
or anything, and I would write that word down on the calendar.
The next piece of advice is: Don't trust apps.
Why? Because as I told you, it's a robot.
And so, you're going to be talking... or well,
more than talking, because you don't really talk,
you will be learning with a robot.
In the end, you'll end up speaking like a robot.
And the last and possibly most important tip,
There is no shortcut.
You're not going to learn Spanish in three weeks.
You're not going to learn Spanish in three months.
And you're not going to learn Spanish with a magic course,
that will make you learn Spanish in 7 days.
Learning Spanish is a constant process, constant I repeat,
It is very constant, which you have to go through.
And lastly, I'm going to give you an extra tip,
which is the best way to learn anything in life.
And you learn, if you can, of course, with experiences.
Learn through experience. Why?
Because when you learn with experiences, not only
you are not holding it in your head, but thanks to
that experience, you're going to be retaining it here, too.
And it's easier, in the future, to remember what you learned.
Well, this advice may sound a little sentimental,
but that's how I learned English.
I learned English with friends,
I learned English with coworkers,
and I learned English with people from my everyday life,
with the person from the bakery,
with the person from the supermarket,
with the person from the restaurant. Then,
That English that I learned, I think or hope, that I will never
I'm going to forget about it. And if you have any advice, I'd love to.
that you share it with other Hispanophiles,
to help them learn Spanish more easily.
And that's it. Don't forget to turn on notifications,
right down here... Well, subscribe to the channel,
and activate notifications, because this weekend,
I'm going to surprise you with a video, which until now,
I've never done it on the channel.
So you can't miss it!